<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Neil Spink</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/</link><description>Recent content on Neil Spink</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neilspink.ch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Your Online Shop Isn’t Selling (And What I’d Do If I Were CEO)</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2026-01-18-onlineshop-search-results/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2026-01-18-onlineshop-search-results/</guid><description>Recently, I went looking for a USB-C monitor. I typed exactly that into the onlineshop of the nearest electronics store getting nothing relevant back. Confused, I ran the same search on four more major Swiss retailers. One showed only cables. Two didn’t list any monitors. One buried the relevant products under five unrelated results. Only one got it right.
Maybe “Bildschirm” was the better term? Tried that. No improvement.
Your search engine is your sales team.</description></item><item><title>100days.ink — A Commitment Engine</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2025-09-07-100days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2025-09-07-100days/</guid><description>I’ve been building 100days.ink, a small app with a big purpose: help people commit to something for 100 days and actually follow through.
The rules are simple:
Write down your 100-day commitment. Pick a start date. Decide if it’s private, public, or shared with the community. Support the idea with a tip. That’s it. No feeds. No distractions. Just you versus the next 100 days.
The idea came from watching I Worked Out Like David Goggins for 100 Days.</description></item><item><title>AheadFork: Exploring Forks Ahead of Upstream (Python)</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-11-27-aheadfork/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-11-27-aheadfork/</guid><description>I wrote AheadFork, a small Python tool that helps explore GitHub forks that are ahead of their upstream repository—where contributors have built new code on top of existing projects. Using the GitHub REST API, it checks each fork of a given repo, compares its master branch against upstream, and reports how many commits it is ahead or behind, along with stars and last push date. This makes it easy to spot active forks that may contain interesting features, bug fixes, or experiments worth tracking.</description></item><item><title>Recaptures: a one‑minute screen capture journal (C#)</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-05-14-recaptures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-05-14-recaptures/</guid><description>A tiny Windows utility that snapshots your screen every minute and ships it to storage—useful for a visual work log.</description></item><item><title>Tidbit: A Discord Bot That Searches Twitter</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-04-20-discord-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-04-20-discord-bot/</guid><description>I built Tidbit, a lightweight Discord bot that listens for mentions and turns your words into smart Twitter searches. By pulling the ten longest words in a message, Tidbit queries Twitter (via the API) and replies with the most relevant tweet it finds—URLs stripped for clarity. The project is fully containerized with Docker, uses discord.js v14 and the twitter-api-v2 library, and is easily configurable through environment variables. Tidbit is released under the GNU General Public License v3 (GPL-3.</description></item><item><title>Building a Mood Barometer: The IoT Workshop at Swiss Re</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-02-16-iot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-02-16-iot/</guid><description>In early 2020, I hosted a hands-on IoT workshop at Swiss Re. The challenge? Build a mood barometer — a physical dial that reflects the emotional &amp;ldquo;weather&amp;rdquo; of a space.
Each team flashed an ESP32, wrote Arduino code to read mood values over HTTP or MQTT, and moved a dial to match. No soldering — just ESP32 boards, stepper motors, and a magnet sensor wired up to detect calibration points. A few hundred francs in parts.</description></item><item><title>Map the metadata of your YAML</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2019-12-31-yaml-dredger/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2019-12-31-yaml-dredger/</guid><description>yaml-dredger I thought it would be useful to analyze the structure of YAML files at scale.
YAML gets used for everything — APIs, configurations, Kubernetes, data specs — and often no one really knows what&amp;rsquo;s in the files. This script crawls a folder of YAML and gives you a kind of map: what entities exist, what fields they have, and where they show up.
It&amp;rsquo;s not pretty — but it works.</description></item><item><title>Subutai P2P Cloud + Minecraft Hosting</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2018-10-10-subutaiminecraft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2018-10-10-subutaiminecraft/</guid><description>Why Subutai’s P2P cloud grabbed me and how I wrote a Minecraft hosting blueprint to be part of it.</description></item><item><title>Speed Comparison: Ember.js Client &amp; Server Heat Test</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2016-12-20-ember/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2016-12-20-ember/</guid><description>Back in late 2016 I wanted to get my hands dirty with Ember.js and modern JavaScript frameworks, so I started a small side project called Speed Comparison. The idea was simple: measure website performance and make it easy to compare results.
I split the work into eight weekly sprints so I could learn by shipping something small each week. The project ended up with two main parts:
Client (Ember.js): a responsive UI for visualizing the speed scores Server (Node.</description></item></channel></rss>