<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>Posts on Neil Spink</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Neil Spink</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.118.2</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neilspink.ch/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>100days.ink — A Commitment Engine</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2025-09-07-100days/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2025-09-07-100days/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been building <a href="https://100days.ink">100days.ink</a>, a small app with a big purpose:
help people commit to something for 100 days and actually follow through.</p>
<p>The rules are simple:</p>
<ul>
<li>Write down your 100-day commitment.</li>
<li>Pick a start date.</li>
<li>Decide if it’s private, public, or shared with the community.</li>
<li>Support the idea with a tip.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s it. No feeds. No distractions. Just you versus the next 100 days.</p>
<p><img src="100daysink.png" alt="100Days.ink landing page"></p>
<p>The idea came from watching <a href="https://youtu.be/vWU5O7cK7aI?si=Qvuerw0Zx3Y68PMf">I Worked Out Like David Goggins for 100 Days</a>.
It’s entertaining, but also shows what happens when you truly commit to a goal. Momentum compounds when you consistently deliver.
It lit the spark for my own 100-day project, but instead of doing fitness, I wanted to program again. And why not build a commitment engine that backs you on that venture: something that turns promises into action and accountability into a game you can actually win.</p>
<p>I wanted massive scaling capacity and chose Firebase. Their NoSQL backend gives granular access control and easy auth.
I added Firebase Storage for images, because words aren’t always enough.
On top of that I run a free cron-job.org task to push daily reminders with short coaching notes to your mailbox, plus a weekly digest.</p>
<p>To make it dynamic, the AI coach changes tone: if you skip check-ins, the “temperature” gets dialed up a bit. More direct. More urgent.
The app is minimal on purpose. A fun MVP.</p>
<p>I didn’t expect login and email to be the hardest parts of the project. If registration emails land in spam, your app is dead before it starts.</p>
<p><img src="commitment-saved-confirmation.png" alt="100Days.ink registration page with spam folder notice"></p>
<p>Even with a notice to check spam, few people actually completed registration.</p>
<p><img src="spam-mail2.png" alt="Spam mail example"></p>
<p>You get what you pay for. And this one-size-fits-all backend forced me to jam Firebase’s user model into mine.
Registration emails come from their *.firebaseapp.com domain. That’s a red flag for spam filters when your sending domain is 100days.ink.</p>
<p>The Firestore database was very practical.</p>
<p>I liked building in Next.js with TypeScript. API routes, file-based routing, server + client in one place — good first experience.
I’ve worked with Angular and completed a project in Ember.js, but moving into the React ecosystem was great.</p>
<p>Making it mobile friendly was important to me. You get a link every day to reflect on your 100-day mission.</p>
<img src="UI-day1.jpg" alt="Day 1 reflection" width="375" />
<p>Every day, the system runs a user’s most recent reflections through OpenAI, combining their goal, coaching style, and recent behavior to generate personalized advice and an email subject line in the coach’s voice.
It tags reflections with a “vibe” (grit, frustration, etc.) and adjusts tone based on engagement — trying to keep users moving forward.</p>
<p><img src="emails.png" alt="Example emails"></p>
<p>I was worried OpenAI usage might blow up my budget, so I limited output length and kept prompts tight.
It turns out the cost was laughably low.</p>
<p><img src="openai.png" alt="OpenAI costs"></p>
<p>I pushed 100days on X and ran a small ad campaign, but it didn’t gain much traction.
In September I started building social features, but ultimately decided to wrap the project.</p>
<p><img src="github.png" alt="Github commits"></p>
<p>There were several cool parts of the project:</p>
<ul>
<li>AI coaching personalities (data-driven archetypes + guardrails)</li>
<li>A daily coaching pipeline built on reflections + goal context</li>
<li>Time-limited “mission day” links (mobile-first)</li>
<li>Reflection timeline with optional image uploads + failure UX</li>
<li>Email engine using Markdown templates (daily + weekly digest)</li>
<li>Stripe “tip” checkout as a simple monetization path</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m keeping the repo private for now. If you’re curious, I’ll share a walkthrough or selected snippets.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>AheadFork: Exploring Forks Ahead of Upstream (Python)</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-11-27-aheadfork/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-11-27-aheadfork/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote <strong>AheadFork</strong>, a small Python tool that helps explore GitHub forks that are ahead of their upstream repository—where contributors have built new code on top of existing projects. Using the GitHub REST API, it checks each fork of a given repo, compares its <code>master</code> branch against upstream, and reports how many commits it is ahead or behind, along with stars and last push date. This makes it easy to spot active forks that may contain interesting features, bug fixes, or experiments worth tracking. AheadFork is simple to run with Python 3 and <code>requests</code>, and it’s released on GitHub for anyone curious about how projects evolve through their forks.</p>
<p>Check out the <a href="https://github.com/neilspink/aheadfork">source on GitHub</a> and try it out on your favorite repos.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Recaptures: a one‑minute screen capture journal (C#)</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-05-14-recaptures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-05-14-recaptures/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-i-built-it">Why I built it<a href="#why-i-built-it" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h2>
<p>In 2020, <em>everyone</em> was home; Parents, kids, teachers. My son had school on the computer and I had work. Like many parents, “Trust is good, control is better,” my wife said, so I built a way to see what my son was actually doing.</p>
<p>I wanted a <strong>visual record of work</strong> without manual logging—something I could glance back on to reconstruct what he did.  So I wrote <strong>Recaptures</strong>, a tiny Windows app that <strong>screenshots once per minute</strong> and <strong>uploads the JPEG</strong> to remote storage.</p>
<ul>
<li>Language: <strong>C# / .NET (WinForms host)</strong></li>
<li>Packages: <strong>FluentFTP</strong> for FTPS, <strong>Serilog</strong> for logs</li>
<li>Strategy: minimal timer + full-screen capture + JPEG quality control</li>
</ul>
<p>Repo: <code>https://github.com/neilspink/recaptures</code></p>
<h3 id="prolog">Prolog<a href="#prolog" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h3>
<p>My son hated it. When he was caught not working on school stuff, he quickly discovered why: the app. :) It was fun (for me) watching him try to hack it in real time.</p>
<p>For him, it was surveillance. For me, it was peace of mind. But I’ll give him credit: it <strong>raised his IT game</strong>, and that, in a way, was also part of the lesson.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Tidbit: A Discord Bot That Searches Twitter</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-04-20-discord-bot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-04-20-discord-bot/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<p>I built <strong>Tidbit</strong>, a lightweight Discord bot that listens for mentions and turns your words into smart Twitter searches. By pulling the ten longest words in a message, Tidbit queries Twitter (via the API) and replies with the most relevant tweet it finds—URLs stripped for clarity. The project is fully containerized with Docker, uses <code>discord.js v14</code> and the <code>twitter-api-v2</code> library, and is easily configurable through environment variables. Tidbit is released under the <strong>GNU General Public License v3 (GPL-3.0)</strong>, so you are free to use, modify, and share it under the same terms.</p>
<p><img src="example.png" alt="Discord chat screenshot"></p>
<p>Check out the <a href="https://github.com/neilspink/Tidbit-Doctor-Strew">source on GitHub</a> and feel free to run it in your own server or extend it with new features.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Building a Mood Barometer: The IoT Workshop at Swiss Re</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-02-16-iot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2020-02-16-iot/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<p>In early 2020, I hosted a hands-on IoT workshop at Swiss Re. The challenge? Build a mood barometer — a physical dial that reflects the emotional &ldquo;weather&rdquo; of a space.</p>
<p>Each team flashed an ESP32, wrote Arduino code to read mood values over HTTP or MQTT, and moved a dial to match. No soldering — just ESP32 boards, stepper motors, and a magnet sensor wired up to detect calibration points. A few hundred francs in parts. Build it. Ship it. Make it move.</p>
<p>I prepped three micro-projects to help them get there:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/neilspink/mood-barometer"><strong>mood-barometer</strong></a>:<br>
ESP32-based analog mood dial powered by a stepper motor and magnet sensor. It listens for MQTT messages and moves the needle to happy, neutral, or sad. Includes the GIMP dial art and Fusion 360 housing.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/neilspink/mood-infrared-controlled"><strong>mood-infrared-controlled</strong></a>:<br>
For teams that didn’t want to mess with networking. Used any IR remote to manually set the mood. Just fun to play with.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/neilspink/mood-mqtt-client-nodejs"><strong>mood-mqtt-client-nodejs</strong></a>:<br>
Node.js MQTT publisher — a CLI tool to simulate inputs or act as a bridge between UI and device.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h3 id="barometer-prototypepicture-frontjpg"><img src="picture-front.jpg" alt="Barometer prototype"><a href="#barometer-prototypepicture-frontjpg" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h3>
<h3 id="back-of-the-barometerpicture-backjpg"><img src="picture-back.jpg" alt="Back of the Barometer"><a href="#back-of-the-barometerpicture-backjpg" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h3>
<hr>
<p>A colleague stepped up and helped design a <strong>custom PCB</strong>, so teams weren&rsquo;t fumbling with jumper wires all day. That took things to another level. Everyone had something solid to build with — and take home.</p>
<p>Some used a <strong>local MQTT bridge</strong>, others connected to <strong>Azure IoT Hub</strong> with device provisioning and telemetry reporting. A few hundred francs in hardware, a shared repo, and some printed cheat sheets — that&rsquo;s all it took.</p>
<p>It turned out to be one of the most satisfying workshops I’ve ever run.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Map the metadata of your YAML</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2019-12-31-yaml-dredger/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2019-12-31-yaml-dredger/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<h2 id="yaml-dredger">yaml-dredger<a href="#yaml-dredger" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h2>
<p>I thought it would be useful to analyze the structure of YAML files at scale.</p>
<p>YAML gets used for everything — APIs, configurations, Kubernetes, data specs — and often no one really knows what&rsquo;s in the files. This script crawls a folder of YAML and gives you a kind of map: what entities exist, what fields they have, and where they show up.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not pretty — but it works. And it’s fast enough for real datasets.</p>
<h2 id="why-i-built-it">Why I Built It<a href="#why-i-built-it" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h2>
<p>Back in 2001 at Swiss Re, I helped build a large reporting system on DB2. We relied heavily on metadata — not just to document views but to generate and trace them. That stuck with me.</p>
<p>Years later, while exploring Alibaba Cloud, I entered their <strong><a href="https://www.alibabacloud.com/blog/cricket-wickets-and-big-data_595336">Cricket, Wickets and Big Data</a></strong> challenge. The contest involved analyzing over 1,400 international cricket matches using Alibaba’s big data tools. After completing the Big Data learning path, I was handed the dataset — mostly raw YAML.</p>
<p>This tool helped me break that down. I wanted to know: What entities exist? What the attributes are? Which files contain what?</p>
<p>The project is done in JavaScript, source code available on <a href="https://github.com/neilspink/yaml-dredger">Github</a>.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Subutai P2P Cloud + Minecraft Hosting</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2018-10-10-subutaiminecraft/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2018-10-10-subutaiminecraft/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-subutai-grabbed-me">Why Subutai grabbed me<a href="#why-subutai-grabbed-me" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h2>
<p>Subutai™ is the first real <strong>Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Cloud Computing platform</strong> I’d seen.<br>
Born out of a defense research project, it let anyone create a secure, distributed cloud using spare resources — not Amazon’s, not Google’s, but yours.</p>
<p>The idea of a <strong>democratized cloud</strong> felt ahead of its time, and I wanted in.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="my-contribution-minecraft-hosting">My contribution: Minecraft hosting<a href="#my-contribution-minecraft-hosting" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h2>
<p>Subutai apps are packaged as <strong>Blueprints</strong> — JSON templates you can share on the Bazaar marketplace.<br>
I wrote one for <strong>Minecraft hosting</strong>:</p>
<p>👉 <a href="https://github.com/neilspink/subutai-blueprint-minecraft">github.com/neilspink/subutai-blueprint-minecraft</a></p>
<p>With it, anyone could spin up a Minecraft server inside their own P2P cloud in minutes. It wasn’t just about gaming — it was a way to show that Subutai could power <em>everyday communities</em>, not just IoT or enterprise workloads.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="running-two-nodes-in-switzerland">Running two nodes in Switzerland<a href="#running-two-nodes-in-switzerland" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h2>
<p>I didn’t just code it; I ran it. For two years I hosted <strong>two Subutai nodes in Switzerland</strong>, in different locations. One in my flat, another in a family member’s home.</p>
<p>That gave me my own tiny but real <strong>private cloud</strong>, geo-separated and resilient enough to run the Minecraft world my son and his friends played in. It proved the point: with Subutai, ordinary people could build and control their own cloud.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="what-it-meant">What it meant<a href="#what-it-meant" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h2>
<p>Writing the Minecraft blueprint and hosting those nodes made decentralization personal. It wasn’t theory — it was my hardware, my rules, my cloud.</p>
<p>That’s the future I’d still like to see: <strong>clouds that belong to people, not just corporations.</strong></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Speed Comparison: Ember.js Client &amp; Server Heat Test</title><link>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2016-12-20-ember/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://neilspink.ch/posts/2016-12-20-ember/</guid><description>&amp;lt;no value&amp;gt;</description><content type="text/html" mode="escaped"><![CDATA[<p>Back in late 2016 I wanted to get my hands dirty with <strong>Ember.js</strong> and modern JavaScript frameworks, so I started a small side project called <strong>Speed Comparison</strong>. The idea was simple: measure website performance and make it easy to compare results.</p>
<p>I split the work into <strong>eight weekly sprints</strong> so I could learn by shipping something small each week. The project ended up with two main parts:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Client (Ember.js):</strong> a responsive UI for visualizing the speed scores</li>
<li><strong>Server (Node.js):</strong> hosted on <strong>Google Cloud</strong>, collecting and serving the performance data</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-api">The API<a href="#the-api" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h3>
<p>The server exposed a small <strong>REST API</strong> for pulling site performance scores. I documented it with <strong>Swagger (OpenAPI 2.0)</strong> so it was easy to test and extend. Here’s a slice of the spec:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">swagger</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;2.0&#39;</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">info</span>:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>  <span style="color:#f92672">title</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">cloude.ch pagespeed API</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>  <span style="color:#f92672">description</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">Use to call Google Pagespeed Insights</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>  <span style="color:#f92672">version</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;1.0.0&#34;</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">host</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">api.clouded.ch</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">basePath</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">/api</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">paths</span>:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>  <span style="color:#f92672">/sites</span>:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#f92672">get</span>:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>      <span style="color:#f92672">summary</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">Pagespeed insight</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>      <span style="color:#f92672">parameters</span>:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>        - <span style="color:#f92672">name</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">url</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>          <span style="color:#f92672">in</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">query</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>          <span style="color:#f92672">required</span>: <span style="color:#66d9ef">true</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>          <span style="color:#f92672">type</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">string</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>      <span style="color:#f92672">responses</span>:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>        <span style="color:#f92672">200</span>:
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>          <span style="color:#f92672">description</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">pagespeed 0 to 100</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>That endpoint would hit Google Pagespeed Insights, crunch the result, and return a number between 0 and 100. Nothing fancy, but it got the job done.</p>
<h3 id="stack--hosting">Stack &amp; Hosting<a href="#stack--hosting" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h3>
<p>The client was pure <strong>Ember.js</strong> (my first project with it), deployed on <strong>Firebase Hosting</strong>. The backend was a lightweight <strong>Node.js</strong> app (also my first time using Node), running on <strong>Google Cloud</strong>. That setup gave me a good crash course in getting a front end and an API out into the wild, not just running locally. It was the first time I stitched together a full stack on Google platforms, and it felt pretty satisfying to see the pieces talk to each other.</p>
<h3 id="the-code">The Code<a href="#the-code" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
      stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
      <path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3"></path>
      <line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12"></line>
   </svg></a></h3>
<p>If you want to check it out:</p>
<ul>
<li>Client (Ember.js): <a href="https://github.com/neilspink/speed-comparison-client">speed-comparison-client</a></li>
<li>Server: <a href="https://github.com/neilspink/speed-comparison-server">speed-comparison-server</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>